All right, then. Let's begin. So, could
you tell me your full name, please? My
full name is Suhi Kang. Suhi Kang. Okay.
And are you working or are you a
student? I'm currently a graduate
student. I am finishing up my MA in the
United States.
And could you tell me about your major?
Uh so, I major in cinema and media
studies. And basically, what the major
does is it looks at film and other kinds
of media like TV shows, music, um social
media, and it analyzes
the sort of social significance of the
things that are relevant in the media.
And do you enjoy your major? I do. Um
I've always loved um consuming media for
fun, but getting to look at it from an
academic perspective is
uh it's very enjoyable as well.
Great.
And what do you enjoy doing in your free
time?
In my free time, I like to listen to
music. Um recently, I've gotten into
sort of the algorithm, you know, on the
music listening apps. I love to discover
new songs that are not even a language I
understand, but are familiar genres. So,
maybe, you know, rock or jazz.
Yeah, that's my new hobby, listening to
music. Right.
Okay, now let's talk about uh saying
thank you. So, have you ever sent a
thank you card to others?
I have, yes. Um
uh a mo- recent thank you card I
remember writing is to my friend, an
American friend in the United States.
Um I got sick um at the end of last
year, but this friend really came
through and helped me with everything.
Uh my parents had to come over and she
helped them
uh helped pick them up from the airport
and she just was a very good friend to
me, so I wanted to thank her. I wrote
her uh you know, a handwritten note and
gave it to her with a present because it
was also her birthday.
>> Mhm.
Okay, perfect. And do you think do
people in your country often say thank
you?
Yes, they do. I think it's sort of a
very um
social expectation to be able to say
thank you in
in uh
socially acceptable ways. So, I guess
saying thank you with a handwritten note
is would be the most um genuine form of
saying thank you, but saying thank you
out loud, you know, it's sort of
everyday for us Koreans. Even when we go
to a store and we don't buy anything and
we just go out, we would say thank you.
>> Mhm.
>> [laughter]
>> Um
and
on what occasions do you say thank you?
Uh I would sort of um divide that into
two occasions. The first one is, like I
said, sort of everyday thank you that I
say, you know, out of um habit more than
anything. You know, when I go to a
store, with strangers, with friends, or
when I bump into someone or someone pick
something up for me on the street. But
the other occasion is um when someone
really does something for me that wasn't
expected of them, but they do it anyway.
Um those are the occasions where I
really want to express my gratitude. So,
I'll write a note or send a long text.
You know, everything's digital now, so I
guess it doesn't have to be handwritten.
Okay, lovely.
Uh now, let's talk about spare time. So,
do you often have free time?
Uh I do. Um especially in the summer,
uh, I don't have classes, so I am
technically free all day. Um, I spend I
have spent most of last week just
meeting up with friends, but when I'm in
the US and I have free time, I like to
just go to campus and work on
uh, my essays or read a book. I like to
not be at home when I'm doing those
things. So, even though I will go
outside to campus, I will still sort of
do things that allow me to be by myself.
Lovely.
And
would you like to have more free time in
the future?
Well, I wouldn't say no to any more free
time, but I am, um, sort of excited for
the next part of my life, which is
um, going to be a bit busy and I do miss
that kind of routine, going to class
every day and working,
um, as, I guess, a teaching assistant or
a research assistant. I like to have
that routine in my life, so, um, I kind
of miss that, um, hustle and bustle. I'm
looking forward to that, actually.
Okay, perfect.
All right, that'll do us for part one of
the test and now we'll move on to part
two.
So, I'll just give you your question.
So, I'll just give you that here and
I'll give you a pencil there, too. So,
yeah, now I'll give you 1 minute to do
some note taking for that, so you can
write there. All right?
Okay, that's 1 minute.
So, uh,
I'll ask you the question now. So, could
you describe a person who you think
wears unusual clothes?
The person that I would like to describe
who wears unusual clothes is my friend,
um, she's called Taylan.
And she is actually not, uh,
a person that I have met in real life.
She's an online friend that I met
through you know social networking. We
bonded over our love of movies. She is
currently a student preparing for an
exam.
And her clothes are very
doll-like. If you've ever seen you know
little dolls that wear bonnets, flowy
skirts, lacy you know like tops.
That's her and her clothes are always
patterned so beautifully. They have
pictures of you know little lambs,
animals or you know pottery on them.
They're very beautiful blue and pink. I
think her clothes are unusual because um
I think in Korea the trend now is sort
of being kind of hip and
um
very uh fashionable, trendy. But her
clothes actually evoke older time. A
very feminine and girly maybe even from
you know the Victorian age you know.
They're very long skirts. So I think she
is very unique and probably brave for
wearing those clothes. Maybe not in this
weather but you know in real life I
think people will probably see her and
also think that she is very unique.
We're at about 1:40 there now. Okay. So
yeah the the maximum is 2 minutes. So
yes. Um yeah good. And do you think
there's a difference between how people
dress when they're at work and when
they're in their free time?
Uh yes absolutely. At work
there's not only the social expectation
of having to be sort of
you know not very flashy, be sort of fit
in an office environment especially if
you work in an office or have a job that
has to um deal with a lot of cus-
customer, like um in a coffee shop, for
example. You do If you stand out, I
guess that's kind of um
people will judge you if you stand out
in that sort of environment where you
have to be around other people. But, in
their free time, people can really dress
however they like. I think they're more
free to express themselves through their
clothing. For example, um
me myself, if uh I have had an office
job um before, and I wouldn't really
wear, you know, a tank top to an office,
but, you know, when I'm going out with
friends and or going on a picnic on the
river, I would definitely wear that. So,
that's the kind of difference. Yes.
Great.
So, now we'll uh move on to part three
of the test, so we'll keep it going.
Uh
let me just get the timer.
Okay. So, yeah, now on to the third
part.
Uh so, do you think it is a good idea to
buy clothes online?
I do think it's a very good idea um to
buy clothes online.
Uh first, I think there are so many more
options. Um it's very easy to search for
what you want nowadays. And uh find a
store online store that has that exact
thing that you want. But, offline, it
takes, you know, um
you have to walk around.
Um you need to go upstairs, you know,
like look in every nook and cranny of
the store. But, online, you can just do
that with a click. So, I think it I do
think it's a good idea. And also, it's a
lot accessible for a lot more accessible
for people who might not live in a big
city like Seoul.
Um when I live in the states, I live in
a pretty small city. So, there aren't
many clothing stores out there, but
online, buying clothes online, it makes
me possible to find the styles that I
want
um
uh without going to a big city that is
probably 3 hours away.
>> Mhm. Yes, yes, indeed.
And what are the differences between
clothes worn by older people and those
worn by younger people?
I would say the biggest difference is
comfort, especially in Korea.
Um
I think younger people are more willing
to sacrifice a bit of comfort for their
style, which I really admire. I think
it's a great thing. For example, they
might wear higher heels or more
form-fitting clothes.
Um not everyone, of course, but a lot
more people might be willing to do that
in the younger generation than in the
older generation. When I see the older
generation on the street, they might
wear very loose clothes, like loose
pants, um suitable for the weather.
If it's hot, they there's a special
material in Korea that allows, you know,
like wind to go through the fabric. So,
they might wear clothes made out of
that.
And but uh
I guess the younger generation are kind
of willing to take that risk to be a
little uncomfortable if in order to look
good. Mhm. Yeah. Do you think it's
important to be fashionable?
I do. Um I did not used to think that. I
used to think that, you know, it's just
clothes. What Why does it matter? But
then, I found out about, you know,
thrift shopping, um vintage shopping,
and
how to um be fashionable while still,
you know, protecting the environment,
and also um expressing yourself through
clothes, because there are a lot more
things that you can find at the thrift
store that are more unique than things
sold in regular store. So, when I find
that unique item, I feel like it's
really for me alone, and that has really
kind of shown me the pleasure of
expressing myself through clothing. Yes,
yes. And what effect do you think um
clothing and fashion has on the
environment?
Well, I don't think it's a very um
positive effect as of now. Of course, um
as more people get interested in, you
know, upcycling or vintage, um it might
change, but as of now, I think a lot of
clothes get made, but they don't all get
sold. So, that ex- um excess clothing, I
heard just gets buried in the desert in
Africa somewhere, and there's a big
landfill just full of fashionable
clothes that haven't even gotten sold
yet. So, I think it's important for, you
know, clothing companies to produce
less,
not even um I guess upcycle or, you
know, recycle clothing, just maybe
produce less in the first place
to better um
sort of counter demand and try to meet
that instead of producing just whatever
they can.
Yes, yes. And do you think expensive
clothing is always better than cheaper
clothing?
Mm.
I
actually do
think that in most cases expensive
clothing is better.
Um especially if it's made out of
materials that last longer.
Um if you buy, you know, a 3,000 won
T-shirt, um I don't think it's going to
be made of cotton that is very durable.
But expensive clothing
means that there is a certain guarantee
that the cotton is going to be, you
know, more thick. It's going to be last
longer. So, I guess buying something
even if it's a little more expensive
when you first buy it is
um
ultimately going to be better for the
environment because you don't have to
buy the same thing two or three times.
The lifespan is much longer.
Okay. That'll do us. We're all done
there. Thank you for your time.
>> Thank you. Yes.
All right. So, yeah. Now, let's talk
about the the feedback of the test,
yeah? You know, to be honest, I don't
really have much to say about like
improvements. There's a lot of
positivity to talk about. I'd like to
talk about like the positive things
first, the language you're using. A lot
of nice phrases like when you said you
were sick and this friend really came
through for you. That's a nice
expression we could use.
Um saying thank you.
Um when you mentioned that, you said out
of habit. I think that's a nice
expression. Instead of like I feel like
a lot of students would say, I say thank
you because it is my habit. But nice
expression, I say it out of habit. Out
of habit, yeah?
Um when you talked about your friend in
part two, bonded over our love of good
expression, right? So, I think students
could definitely use phrases like this.
We bonded over our love of music, yeah?
Um
What else have we got? Uh every nook and
cranny, I like that one as well. Good
good expression to use, yeah? When you
go out shopping, you have to look in
every nook and cranny and online is a
lot more convenient.
Uh
good expression as well, sacrifice
comfort for style. You know, that could
be a good one if students are looking
for expressions. Sacrifice A for B, so a
lot of young people sacrifice comfort
for fashion and style. Um,
not many things to say in terms of
grammar. Maybe one time I think we said
like more thick should be thicker, you
know, not a big deal. Um,
just about the difference between go
outside and go out. Um, I'm sure you
know, obviously. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Just
students would confuse that sometimes.
Go outside is more outdoorsy. Yeah, go
out could be going to your campus
library or anything like that. Yeah.
Yeah, but yeah, no, that was a really
good test. So, thank you for coming in.
Yes, lovely. All right.